all right so the question came in can I
just use three Dell
oplex uh instead of carving up a tower
for virtual machines and the answer is
absolutely you totally can do that um I
do have on the screen right now that the
the re the price for the real Optiplex
is when you buy a new one instead of a
refurbished one and as you can see it's
not really a very good
price right I mean this is literally the
same thing uh it's an i7 7 an i5 but
even so you I mean if you get the like
the lower ones the prices don't come
down very much right um even with the I5
it's still $924 compared that to $150
for the stuff I showed you on the
refurbish lists for Amazon um yesterday
so you know I hear what you're saying
when you say about the cost I I think
the best way to do this is to get
multiple uh fitu 530 has Nas was only
like 80 bucks dedicated k2000 GPU yeah
look the point of this is don't you
don't have to use the one that I said
the point is number one find refurbished
Hardware number two consider multiple
nodes physical nodes so you can practice
getting good with all the other things
you need to do like networking maybe
spend that money you saved uh from
getting that big tower for you know
1,700 bucks or whatever and instead of
doing that buy a nice switch that you
can set a ban on and I'm not going to
let you decide about which switch you
want thanks for the thanks for all the
the the hints you guys are putting in
the chat um um the point is you know
having your own actual lab like a lab
like you would build out for a community
college or something if you wanted to
teach people how to set up a computer
lab which is what you're doing is better
that's the main point of the video um
and I'm also going to add that you
definitely should know how to carve up a
tower that's got into a a lot of virtual
machines that can't be done unless you
have a machine that's got a lot of RAM
on it so but it doesn't have to be the
thing you do first right you can as I
said in the in the video you can save
your money up and do that eventually um
in a much far far longer time you're not
going to be there are the the implicit
question in can't I just do it on three
you know $150 nodes you know Hardware
nodes uh can I do the same thing as I
would do on the tower the answer is no
you can't it's not the same thing so not
knowing how to allocate virtual memory
uh not knowing how to use libbert kbm
and Kimu and all of these amazing
commands from the from the command line
which you can do it to a limited extent
on those other nodes but they only have
16 gabes of ram right so I mean you know
you definitely can do that right you can
take one of those nodes one of those
tiny $150 nodes refurbished nodes and
you can split it up into uh a different
virtual machine if you want just like
you could on the bigger Tower to get
good you could definitely do that to
practice but the goal of having a tower
that's got a lot of RAM and a number of
of of cores the goal of that is to truly
understand how to slice it up and to
reassign and to consider things like kbm
you might play around with prox MOX or
xcg or any of these you know different
tools for slicing up these things um and
and that's really the point the point
the point is getting good with
virtualization um at the hardware level
you know and you can't get good with
virtualization
uh on the cheap unless you buy a tower
the tower is going to be way cheaper
than buying I mean go do the price go
price out what it cost to have one month
of of of you know of computer in the
cloud that has anywhere near even the
RAM and CPU cores of $150 refurbished
piece of hardware and then when you do
the math and then you you consider what
it would cost to buy I mean even the
$121,300 when you when you like I'm Mor
mortiz or whatever the word is to to get
that spread out over the course of the
life that you're going to be using that
thing because you you'll have it forever
right because that's the really great
thing about Linux is you'll be able to
run even on that refurbished Hardware on
that tower for a very very long time and
it doesn't need to be super duper High
perform it because that's not a
requirement right your your requirement
is you need a lab you can practice
virtualization setting it up and
everything and if you I I promise you if
you were to try to get that that amount
of resources you would buy back that
computer in the cloud if you were to get
that in the cloud within two months
months so so you know I there might be
some hesitance to actually eventually
drop the money on on a tower that has 50
60 gbytes of Ram or whatever refurbished
or otherwise you know spent over $
thousand dollars on that thing but I
still think it's a priority I think you
should do it I think you should put it
in your plan uh whether you're going to
you're planning on being a web dev or an
operations person if you're going to be
in security and operations you kind of
have to do that that's not an option
that that particular career path
requires it I strongly believe that um I
I've never met I literally have never
met an operations engineer which
includes devops and infrastructure
engineering who does not have a tower
that they regularly allocate there's
occasionally you'll run into devops
people that have only done with done
stuff in the cloud they're more about
they're more Cloud Engineers which is
great there's definitely a career path
in that but I I don't see how you can
call yourself an infrastructure engineer
without knowing how to to to carve up BM
uh on on on an actual Tower um the SS
can do pretty link integration is also
pretty nice to learn absolutely um yeah
if you if you so yeah we should talk we
we have a different video about what
network Hardware should I get and for
that we should probably have a guest
visitor ltan Bob who actually teaches
network engineering or lived for a long
time at the University um had Tannis as
well has got a lot of more networking
knowledge than I have um and we'll we'll
spec out what that piece is um a lot of
this content uh this video is kind of AC
you know kind of sitting in the middle
of two different um video sort of
groupings uh the one is how to get going
and and and the other one is H lab and
it and um this is something that I
promised last year that I kind of backed
off on the promise because there's a lot
to talk about in the home lab and it how
to set up your own home lab and um I
still think we need that content but
that content is probably a year away but
this video is one of those that kind of
fits in both places um in the meantime
until I actually have a home in which to
put a home lab which I don't right now
right now I have an apartment that we're
moving out of and I'm living out of my
car but at you know eventually we will
do a home lab series and I'll I'll I
mean I donated my towers and everything
so I'll start building back Towers
building out my home Lab at home when
that is but that that might be three or
four years away so so for right now
check out het Tannis check out LTM Bob
um those are the people that I can
actually talk about um and maybe void
some of the YouTubers uh there are some
good YouTubers for for home lab stuff
but the question is can I just use three
nodes versus a tower no you need to do
the three node thing maybe you do that
first but eventually you do need to get
the tower so still save that money up
and I don't know do whatever it takes to
save it up you'll get it